

Gariel Giles

Chicago, IL 60641 (773) 918-5081 / hello@gari.codes

PROFESSIONAL () **SUMMARY**

Experienced QA Analyst responsible for making project development more efficient. With a background knowledge in software engineering, understanding quality assurance from more than just the surface level is essential to understanding the development process and development team to work together to achieve all goals.

SKILLS

- Manual Testing
- Test Cases & Test Plans
- Defect & Bug Tracking
- SQA Testing & Agile Methodologies
- API Testing, Postman
- User Acceptance Testing & Training
- Selenium

- JavaScript, Mocha, React, Node, Express
- Git, GitHub
- HTML, CSS, XML
- Java, Ruby
- SQL
- Android Studio
- Data Erasure

WORK HISTORY

QUALITY ASSURANCE ANALYST

04/2019 to 05/2020

Second Life Mac | Skokie, IL

- Gained leadership role in seeing through implementing NetSuite, helping company to migrate to using its first ERP system.
- Created test cases, identified & documented bugs/defects, reporting enhancement requests, and executing testing scenarios.
- Identified and evaluated recurring problems in NetSuite tests, providing detailed documentation of issues for amelioration efforts.
- Responsible for communicating needs and concerns of business with development team.
- Worked with Second Life Mac's erasure company to retrieve needed API information and customer data to help development team integrate NetSuite with Second Life Mac's erasure system.
- User acceptance tester and trainer, designated role to lead and train operations team on NetSuite, new workflow, new processes and reporting.
- Lead manual mobile device testing (Apple and Android products), diagnosing technical issues through quality control methods (i.e defective camera, water damage, etc.).

TECHNICAL SUPPORT SPECIALIST

06/2018 to 04/2019

AT&T | Chicago, IL

- Knowledge of basic technical support to assist customers with troubleshooting.
- Provide answers to customers on our products & their billing, sustaining & explaining charges, navigating through multiple CRM systems, investigating customers' issues & providing resolutions.
- Obtained a leadership role to assist peers in other centers & handling escalated issues on customer accounts by creating cases, reversing errors and changes

customer did not authorize.

EDUCATION \bigcirc

Software Engineering Immersive

10/2020

General Assembly, Remote

Dedicated over 400 hours to Full-Stack Software Engineering from July 2020 to October 2020. Gaining experience in using a variety of programming languages, creating databases, using DOM Manipulation, CRUD, debugging, Git, API testing, and more.

Computer Science And Programming

City Colleges Of Chicago - Wilbur Wright College, Chicago, IL